**Privacy Policy**
==================

Last updated 09 September 2019

This privacy policy governs your use of service (the “Service”) created by Oy Frank Students Ab and the processing of your personal data by Oy Frank Students Ab in context of the Service. The Service is targeted at students providing a plastic student card and a digital student card as well as student benefits.

As regards your personal data processed in context of the Service, the data controller in accordance with the applicable law shall be Oy Frank Students Ab (Business ID 2532163-6), a company duly incorporated under the laws of Finland and having its principal place of business at Fredrikinkatu 55 A, 00100 Helsinki, Finland ("Frank", "we", "us" or "our"). 

**What information does the Service collect and how is it used?**
-----------------------------------------------------------------

We may collect your information through different means, which are explained below.

*   The information you have given to us as part of registration

The Service requires a user account to work. When you register as a user of the Service, we may collect following information:

*   to verify your identification we collect some basic information, such as your name, social security number and mobile phone number;
    
*   information regarding your student status, such as your place of study. 

**The information regarding the use of the Service**

*   When you use the Service, we may process your information in following situations:
*   your activity in the Service, such as when you make purchases, respond to any offers, or download or use applications from us; 
    
*   when you contact us, we may process your information for the purpose of contacting you, or to send you necessary notifications or important information regarding Service.
    
*   The information collected from other sources

For the purpose of providing you the Service, we may collect your information from JOLLA and/or VIRTA and/or KOSKI  databases or Oma Opintopolku-service provided by Finnish National Agency of Education in order to verify your student status. In this context we use the information you have provided upon your registration.

We fetch the following information from JOLLA and/or VIRTA and/or KOSKI and/or Oma Opintopolku -database for student verification purposes: your birthday, the student organisation you are a member of, your attendance status during the current semester and your student number.

From those users of the Service that want to affiliate themselves to a student organisation upon registration we collect also the following information: your major, your place of study, your street address and postal number, your current city or county and country of residence, your email address, your preferred language, and marketing permission which we will pass on to the affiliated student organisation to update their membership records.

In case your place of study has accepted the use of national database VIRTA for student verification purposes, we may in future with your consent, verify your student status from VIRTA database instead of JOLLA database. For the purpose of student status verification, we fetch the following information from VIRTA database: your name, your student number, your preferred language, the period of validity of your right of study, your field of study, information of the student organisations you have affiliated to, your attendance status and the information of the expiration of your right of study.

**Automatically Collected Information** 

Some information we get automatically from your use of Service. The Service may collect and use certain information automatically, such as timestamps and log data relating to the use of the Service, the information about the devices you use to register for an account and to access and use the Service, such as the unique device ID, the IP address of your device, the operating system used, the type of Internet browser used, and the information about the way you use the Service ("Automatically Collected Information"). 

**Location data from the device**

When you use the mobile application, we may with your consent, use GPS technology (or other similar technology) to determine your current location. By means of this, we can target the content of the Service provided to you. We will not share your location data with third parties.

If you do not want us to use your location for the purposes set forth above, you should turn off the location services for the mobile application located in your account settings or in your mobile phone settings and/or within the mobile application. 

### **Do third parties see and/or have access to information collected by the Service?**

Yes. We may disclose your information to third parties in the following cases:

*   to provide the Service (for the purpose of student status verification) when you use or acquire student benefits from a third party via or through this Service;
    
*   as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, requests by competent public authorities, or similar legal process;
    
*   when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
    
*   with our trusted services providers who work on our behalf, and who do not have an independent use of the information we disclose to them or;
    
*   if Oy Frank Students Ab is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of this information, as well as any choices you may have regarding this information.

### **Is the data transferred outside the EU/ EEA?**

Your information is mainly processed within the European Union. Some of the Automatically Collected Information may be processed in the United States. Frank complies with the applicable law when transferring information to the United States or elsewhere outside the European Union.

### **What are my opt-out rights?**

You can stop collection of information easily by deleting the Service. You may also prohibit Frank from using your information for direct marketing purposes or for the purpose of market research and opinion polls. If you want to prohibit the use of your information for marketing purposes, please contact us by email ([privacy@frank.fi](mailto:privacy@frank.fi)) and we will respond to you within a reasonable period of time.

**Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information**
----------------------------------------------------

We will retain information for as long as you use the Service and for a reasonable time thereafter. We will retain Automatically Collected Information for up to 24 months and thereafter may store it in aggregate as long as may be required for the purpose of providing the Service and ensuring its functioning. If you wold like us to delete your personal data as may be provided by the applicable law, please contact us by email (privacy@frank.fi) and we will respond to you within a reasonable period of time. Please note that some or all of the information may be required in order for the Service to function properly.

You may request Frank to grant you access to your information and to correct, update or erase any unnecessary, incorrect or obsolete information collected on you by using the contact details provided below. Such request shall be made in a personally signed or otherwise comparably verified document or by visiting Frank's premises.

**Children**
------------

We do not use the Service to knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us by email at privacy@frank.fi. We will delete such information from our files within a reasonable time.

**Security**
------------

We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the information we process and maintain. For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Service. Please be aware that, although we endeavour to provide reasonable security for the information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

**Changes**
-----------

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy here and informing you via email or in-app notification. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes, as continued use is deemed approval of all changes. You can check the history of this policy at frank.fi/privacy-policy/archive.

**Cookies** 
------------

Cookies are files which are received and transmitted by a device when the Service is used. Frank may use cookies and similar techniques to provide the Service, to improve its quality and to enhance the user experience. By using the Service and consenting to the use of cookies in your browser settings you consent to the use of cookies by Frank. You may prohibit the use of cookies by changing the browser settings. This may, however, affect the user experience of the Service.

**Contact us**
--------------

If you have any questions regarding privacy while using the Service, or have questions about our practices, please contact us via email at privacy@frank.fi.

* * *

**3\. DESCRIPTION OF THE DATA FILE OF FRANK'S SERVICE (September, 09 2019)**

**1\. Data controller**

Oy Frank Students Ab  
Fredrikinkatu 55 A  
00100 Helsinki, FINLAND

Tel. +358 50 3536789

Business ID 2532163-6, place of the registered office Helsinki

**2\. Contact person**

Antti Eronen, tel. +358 50 3536789

**3\. Name of the register**

Frank's customer and user register

**4\. Purpose of processing personal data**

Personal data is processed for three main purposes:

*   The personal data is processed to provide the Service, manage customer relations, send notifications relating to the Service and for customer communication;
    
*   For marketing purposes. Personal data may be used for Frank's marketing purposes, unless prohibited by the user.
    
*   Personal data may be used to improve and develop the Service. 

**5\. Content of register  
**Frank's customer register collects following information regarding the users of the Service:

*   the basic information, such as name, mobile phone number and social security number;
    
*   the student status, such as the information of the place of study and the student number;
    
*   user's activity in the Service, such as purchase history and communication with us.

**6\. Regular sources of personal information**

The Service collects users' personal data via two sources:

*   directly from the users as a part of registration and of the use of Service
    
*   from JOLLA and/or VIRTA and/or KOSKI- databases and/or Oma Opintopolku -service provided by Finnish National Agency of Education for the purpose of student status verification 

**7\. Sharing of personal data  
**Personal data may be disclosed to third parties regularly in the following cases:

*   to provide the Service (for the purpose of student verification) when student benefits, provided by third parties, are used via or through the Service; and
    
*   with trusted service providers who work on our behalf and who do not have an independent right to use the information  

Personal data may also be disclosed to a third party when required by applicable law or requests by competent authorities or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others or to investigate fraud.

**8\. Transfer of personal data outside EU/ETA  
**Personal data is mainly processed within the European Union. Some of the Automatically Collected Information may be processed in the United States. Frank complies with the applicable law when transferring personal data to the United States or elsewhere outside the European Union.

**9\. Security**

We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the information we process and maintain. For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Service. There are different user rights in the database. The user of the system gets maintenance or browsing rights only to the data that is necessary for the use. Each specified user has his/ her own username and password.

The controller abides strictly by the regulated obligation to observe secrecy. The data in relation to a single user of the Service shall be disclosed only due to an obligation based on the law, for instance at the request of the user himself/herself or authorities as provided in the law.

**10\. Privacy rights** 

In accordance with the Section 26 of the Personal Data Act, the user has a right of access to personal data on him/her. The user may use this right by logging into the Service, by leaving a contact request for Frank's Customer Service or by sending a signed access request in writing to the following address:

Oy Frank Students Ab  
'Fredrikinkatu 55 A  
00100 Helsinki

The user may request a copy of his/her personal data free of charge once every (calendar) year.

The request to rectify information related to place of study should be directed to the user's place of study. The user may in general rectify information, provided by the user himself/herself, in the Service.
